The next thing we're going to talk about is heating your blood python.
Generally, especially when you start off small, the baby in like a fifteen gallon aquarium, we're going to be talking about light bulbs as far as heating.
It's going to be the most accessible and affordable way for you to heat a beginning enclosure.
What you're going to need is you're going to need two heat lamp fixtures.
You want to make sure those heat lamp fixtures have a ceramic base, not plastic, plastic melts and it becomes a fire hazard.
We don't want that.
I know people who have burnt their houses down, not buying the correct equipment.
So make sure it is a ceramic base and, also make sure that it's rated the right amount of wattages we're going to be using.
This, generally I recommend people buy the highest rating wattage they can get, that way, in case they need to upgrade the light bulb they're going to be using, they're already ready to go.
This guy, as you can see right here, is only rated for seventy five watts today.
Then we're going to be looking at, is you need two heat bulbs.
You need a day bulb and a night bulb.
Generally, your night bulb, which will be a red bulb or a blue bulb or a black bulb, colored so that the reptile doesn't see it at night so much and it allows them to sleep, is going to be a slightly lower wattage than say, your day bulb, which will be on during the day.
Usually you want like a seventy five watt night bulb and a hundred watt day bulb, something like that.
Every house is going to differ depending on the temperature you keep it in.
So you're going to have to play with your wattages a little bit to find the right temperatures.
What we're really looking for here is somewhere in the eighty five to ninety degree temperature range on the high end for your blood python and in the low end, somewhere around eighty five to eighty degrees.